SUBHANKAR ROUT

Sr. UI/UX Designer | Product Designer

Profile Summary

As a UI/UX Designer, I merge creativity with technical expertise to craft engaging designs, leading numerous projects that boost user satisfaction by an average of 30%. My collaborative efforts with 100+ professionals yield innovative designs that resonate deeply with users, reflecting a commitment to excellence in user experience.

Details

+91 (933)-766-3465

subhankarrout.kiit@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/subhankarrout

Portfolio

www.subhankarrout.in

behance.net/routsubhankar

Skills

- UI/UX Designing
- User Research
- Wire-framing
- Prototyping
- Visual Design
- Interaction Design
- User Interview
- Design System
- Design Methodology
- Information Architecture
- Brand Strategist
- Managing Project
- UI Development-HTML,CSS

Experience

Deligence Technologies Inc.

Jan 2024 - Present

Senior UI/UX Designer

- I revamped a leading educational game's UI/UX, increasing user engagement by 20%, reduced user drop-off rates by 15%.
- As a Senior UI/UX Designer, my tasks include designing wireframes, prototypes, user research and user flows to enhance the overall user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate user feedback into design iterations, resulting in a user satisfaction score increase of 30%.

RPATech

Oct 2020 - Jan 2024

Visual Interaction Designer

- Developed engaging visual content for top-rated online courses, resulting in a 40% increase in course enrollment on platforms like Coursera and Udemy.
- As a Visual Interaction Designer, I crafted user interfaces and experiences for our Robotic Process Automation (RPA) projects.
- Enhanced learning experiences through collaborative stakeholder engagement and effective design solutions.

Education

GIET University Bachelor of Technology (2017 - 2021)

Technologies

- Figma, Adobe XD
- Miro
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe After Effects
- Techsmith Camtasia
- Procreate
- Qualtrics
- Jira, Notion

Language

• **English** (L-S-R-W)

• **Hindi** (L - S - R - W)

• Odia (L-S-R-W)

Interest

Geeta Chanting

Reading & Writing Books

Film Making

Travelling

Certifications

- Product Management Professional Certification (Aha! and Atlassian)
- Completed Google UX Design Professional Certification Course.
- Completed the training program on User Experience Designer Certification Course.
- Brand Management: Aligning Business, Brand and Behavior from London Business School.
- The Fundamental of Digital Marketing by Google.
- How to ChatGPT: Master the Art of Prompt Engineering.

Achievements

- Awarded for excellence in UI Design and efficiency optimization at Deligence Technologies Inc.
- Excellence Awardee at RPATech for Dedication and Service.
- Honored by the AVP at RPATech for exceptional creativity and innovative design contributions.
- Awarded as Best Film Maker at GIET University, Gunupur.
- Runners-up on IEEE GIETU Innovation Challenge.

Extra-curricular Activities

- Authored a published English novel, showcasing creativity and storytelling skills.
- Recognized by the Commissioner of Municipality, Rourkela, for contributions to literature and culture.
- Created and managed the "S4 Cinesphere" YouTube channel, producing music albums and short films during college.
- Featured in news outlets for both for novel and music albums.